

# Rui Oliveira, Software Engineer

A solution-oriented software engineer with initiative and experience managing small and large teams as a skilled and dedicated leader. With a thirst for knowledge and a determination to bring new ideas to life that will benefit others.

#### Experience

# **Software Engineer at Checkmarx**

April 2023 — Present

- Integrated one of the R&D teams responsible for supporting the company's Static Application Security Testing (SAST) product.
- Contributed to the support of the GO language (with an emphasis on Gin framework) and am currently working on the development of a policy management platform (a centralized application for defining and managing an organization's security policies).

# Research Assistant at INESC Technology and Science - Associate Laboratory

March 2022 — November 2022

 Analyzed existing solutions to the problem of scientific data management and, as a result, adapted and applied a new solution to a specific study, the SAIL Project, an initiative that addresses climatic change.

# Freelance Full Stack Developer

April 2022 — July 2023

 Developed and maintained web and mobile applications for a variety of businesses, primarily in the fields of digital marketing, sustainable energy, restaurants, and non-profit organizations.

#### Education

# MSc in Computer and Software Engineering, Universidade do Minho

September 2017 — December 2022

- Enterprise project: Reformed the middleware that allows the treatment of more than 100 routes provided and displayed by TUB (Transportes Urbanos de Braga).
- Specialization: Distributed Systems and Parallel and Distributed Computing.
- Dissertation: Scientific Data Management.

Skills

Leadership and Teamwork,
Self-management, Good Communication,
Critical Thinking, Creativity, Fast Learning

Java, Python, C#, C/C++, JavaScript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, Node.js, React.js, Vue.js, SQL, NoSQL, Docker, Git, Bash, Linux

Languages

**Portuguese** C2

0

English B2

0

Spanish B2

#### Volunteering

### Volunteer at Acolmax, Braga

June 2015 — Present

 Contributed to the provision of annual summer vacations for deprived children in Portugal (in places such as Costa da Caparica, Póvoa de Varzim, Castelo de Neiva, or Vila Praia de Âncora).

### Mentor at Grupo de Jovens Alvorada, Braga

October 2019 — September 2022

 Mentored 15-16 years old in weekly discussions about the world, with the goal of creating a space for them to argue and, more importantly, to stimulate their thinking.

#### Extracurricular

## Member of Green Lab Department at Society Loving the Planet Minho

January 2023 — Present

- Mobilized second-hand fairs with the municipality of Braga, a pioneering movement in the city.
- Integrated the Nautilus project, whose goal was to develop a device that measures
  the flow of water used in changing rooms and thereby increasing awareness of water
  consumption.

# Director of Strategy & Sustainable Development Department at Society Loving the Planet Minho

January 2022 — December 2022

- Initiated a program with elementary schools, whose main goal was to provide children with sustainability and ecology sessions on thematic days.
- Created and maintained internal university partners such as student centers, nuclei, and junior enterprises.

#### Portfolio

#### https://priest110.github.io/

#### Hobbies

- Puzzles and lego
- Reading classic novels
- Sports (particularly football and chess)
- Gardening (especially Bonsai)